Anthony Mendez

mendezanthony608@gmail.com | github.com/m-r-q-w-e-r-t-y | linkedin.com/in/anthony00

OBJECTIVE

Seeking a summer 2022 software engineering internship/part-time work. Creative web developer with 2-years of full-stack development experience and 5-years of experience learning and implementing algorithms. A leader with a background in scrum methodology as a Developer and a Project Manager

EDUCATION

University at Buffalo, The State University of New York

Jan 2021-May 2023

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Courses: Algorithms, Systems Programming, Data Structures, OOP

SKILLS

Languages: Python, React, Node.js, JavaScript, Swift, C

Version Control: Git, GitHub

Technologies: Unix, VS Code, Docker, Xcode, NPM, Azure, Android Studio

Apps: Google Suite, ZenHub, GitHub, Canva

EXPERIENCE

Codepath.org

Buffalo, NY

iOS Tech Fellow Jul 2021-Present

- Developed and debugged 4 full-stack iOS applications using Swift, which implemented RESTful API clients that communicate via HTTP requests to perform CRUD operations using Parse4App. Projects include: movie details app, Twitter, Instagram, and Yelp clones
- Led a successful iteration of Codepath's iOS course, where 90% of the starting cohort received a certificate of completion
- Accomplished by teaching 15 technical lab lessons to aid students in their development of 3 full-stack iOS applications

Everest Reinsurance Warren, NJ

Software Engineer Intern

Jun 2021-Aug 2021

- Co-developed an automated Python script in an Azure Container that eliminates manual data entry from PDF to Excel.
 Projected to save \$30k annually
- Solution received a 90% average accuracy rating by using cross-validation testing using Azure Form Recognizer
- Coordinated project sprints and ensured every task was precise to the scope

IBM Buffalo, NY

Accelerate: Software Engineer Program

Jun 2021-Aug 2021

• Collaborated with 5 program members to implement a to-do app and personnel lookup page using React and Node.js utilizing scrum methodology in our workflow. Learned how client-side technologies work with back-end

PROJECTS

Independent (CodeHub)

Feb 2021-Present

Full-Stack Web Developer

• Developing an open-source code documentation tool that helps instructors explain code by inserting detailed comments which appear only when a student or user scrolls onto a new section of the code (React, Node.js, MongoDB, Docker)

Independent (Canvas) Aug 2021-Dec 2021

Full-Stack Web Developer

Created a public canvas drawing web app using no frameworks or external libraries with 4-teammates for an audience of 32 students. Received an A+ based on usability and implementing custom: HTTP, AJAX, templating, and CRUD handlers.
 Other implementations include encryption, authentication, sockets, privacy, and security (Python, Javascript, Docker, HTML, CSS)